export const MANAGEMENTINLIVINGA2019 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Oral rehydration therapy is a fluid replacement used to save the life of babies with",
A: "diarrhoea.",
B: "meningitis.",
C: "chicken pox.",
D: "measles.",
answer: "A. diarrhoea.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Hormones which promote growth changes in adolescent girls are produced in the",
A: "vagina.",
B: "cervix.",
C: "uterus.",
D: "ovaries.",
answer: "D. ovaries.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Acid rain causes",
A: "destruction to soil nutrients.",
B: "depletion to the ozone layer",
C: "global warming.",
D: "land erosion.",
answer: "A. destruction to soil nutrients.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Personal hygiene is very important to the adolescent because of increased",
A: "physical changes.",
B: "sexual drive.",
C: "hormonal action.",
D: "emotional changes.",
answer: "A. physical changes.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. A well ventilated room is always",
A: "clean and neat.",
B: "cool and fresh.",
C: "warm and comfortable.",
D: "spacious and cold.",
answer: "B. cool and fresh.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Peer pressure is strong among adolescents mostly because",
A: "they are sensitive to their friend’s opinion,",
B: "parents do not have time for their children.",
C: "society does not frown on it.",
D: "parents are too lenient on their children.",
answer: "A. they are sensitive to their friend’s opinion.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Plain wooden board is best dried in a",
A: "hot airy place.",
B: "warm airy place.",
C: "shady place.",
D: "cool airy place.",
answer: "A. hot airy place.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Consumers’ complains help manufacturers to",
A: "advertise products.",
B: "cut down cost",
C: "improve products.,",
D: "improve labelling.",
answer: "C. improve products.,",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. When black is mixed with another colour it forms a",
A: "hue.",
B: "tint.",
C: "shades",
D: "tone.",
answer: "C. shades",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. One helpful way of reducing stress is",
A: "smoking.",
B: "relaxation.’^",
C: "studying.",
D: "eating.",
answer: "B. relaxation.’^",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A house and its neighbourhood facilities is the same as",
A: "houses in a community",
B: "shelter with roofs and walls.",
C: "concept of housing,",
D: "structure with all facilities.",
answer: "D. structure with all facilities.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Kitchen designs include",
A: "parallel layout.",
B: "horizontal layout.",
C: "vertical layout.",
D: "rectangular layout.",
answer: "A. parallel layout.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The beginning of menstruation usually indicates a girl’s readiness for",
A: "sex.",
B: "child bearing.",
C: "marriage.",
D: "dating.",
answer: "B. child bearing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A fuse is likely to blow if",
A: "a spoilt appliance is used.",
B: "a circuit is overloaded.",
C: "an appliance is used for a long time.",
D: "the current is low.",
answer: "B. a circuit is overloaded.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Chairbacks, pictures and macramé are examples of",
A: "accessories.",
B: "soft furnishing.",
C: "hard furnishing.",
D: "fixtures.",
answer: "B. soft furnishing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. People whose body mass index (BMI) is above 30 kg/m3 are said to be",
A: "overweight.",
B: "obese",
C: "gluttons.",
D: "overfed.",
answer: "B. obese",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Practices that contribute to wellbeing of body, mind and freedom from disease best describes",
A: "healthy body.",
B: "healthy lifestyle",
C: "health status.",
D: "health habit.",
answer: "B. healthy lifestyle",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. In interior decoration, which of the following colours can easily be combined with any colour?",
A: "Red",
B: "Green",
C: "Brown",
D: "Blue",
answer: "C. Brown",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Paint, grease, ink and rust are examples of",
A: "mineral stains.",
B: "chemical stains.",
C: "vegetable stains.",
D: "biological stains.",
answer: "B. chemical stains.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Caveat is",
A: "alimony paid to a woman after divorce.",
B: "a written objection against the performance of marriage.",
C: "an argument between prospective spouses.",
D: "a secret marriage between two lovers in court.",
answer: "B. a written objection against the performance of marriage.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A sexually transmitted infection that can be prevented through immunization is",
A: "hepatitis B.",
B: "syphilis.",
C: "HIV/AIDS.",
D: "chlamydia.",
answer: "A. hepatitis B.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The most common cause of the depletion of the ozone layer is",
A: "fluoride compounds.",
B: "sulphur oxides.",
C: "nitrogen oxide.",
D: "chloroflurocarbons.",
answer: "D. chloroflurocarbons.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Consequences of masturbation include \nI. a feeling of guilt and embarrassment \nII. bruising the genital organ leading to serious infection \nIII. premature ejaculation \nIV. forming a habit which cannot be broken",
A: "I & II only",
B: "II &III only",
C: "I. II & III only",
D: "I, II, III & IV",
answer: "A. I & II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A marriage in which there is more than one wife, to the husband is called",
A: "polygamy.",
B: "polyandry.",
C: "polygyny.",
D: "monogamy.",
answer: "C. polygyny.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. During the pre-natal development, two weeks to three months is a period of formation of",
A: "a zygote.",
B: "an embryo.",
C: "a foetus,",
D: "a baby.",
answer: "B. an embryo.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Bank drafts are used in paying school fees mostly because",
A: "they are safe to use.",
B: "there is certainty of payment.",
C: "it cannot get lost.",
D: "most schools prefer using it.",
answer: "B. there is certainty of payment.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following statements are true about decision making? \nI. It is a process. \nII. It occurs at all the stages of the managerial process. \nIII It is the core of management. \nIV. It involves planning, implementation and evaluation.",
A: "I & II only",
B: "II & IV only",
C: "I, II & IV only",
D: "I, II & III only",
answer: "D. I, II & III only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The most important consideration in the choice of a house is",
A: "economic status.",
B: "location.",
C: "family size.",
D: "neighbourhood.",
answer: "B. location.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Pick the odd one out from the following set of values.",
A: "Love",
B: "Purity",
C: "Cooperation",
D: "Integrity",
answer: "A. Love (The others are all societal values)",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The process of reducing the amount of time and energy required to accomplish a task is",
A: "time management.",
B: "work simplification.",
C: "dovetailing activities.",
D: "energy management.",
answer: "B. work simplification.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]